[MUSIC]
[موسيقى]
AdaBoost uses this slightly intimidating formula to figure out what w hat t should
يستخدم AdaBoost ذلك، بصيغة بها قدر أقل من الثقة، لاكتشاف ما الذي يجب أن تكون عليه Ŵt ،
be, but it has to be pretty intuitive if you look at it in a bit more detail.
ولكنها ستكن بديهية للغاية إذا تناولتها بقدر أكير من التفصيل.
This formula is derived from a famous theorem, AdaBoost theorem,
وتشتق هذه الصيغة من نظرية مشهورة، ألا وهي نظرية AdaBoost،
which I want to mention very briefly towards the end of the module.
والتي أود أن أتطرق إليها باختصار شديد مع انتهاء هذه الوحدة.
But it's the formula that lets you find classifiers that keep getting better and
ولكنها صيغة تسمح لك بالعثور على مصنفات تقوم بأداء أفضل وأفضل
better, and help boosting to get to the optimal solution.
وتساعد على التعزيز للحصول على الحل الأمثل.
So, lets look at this one in a little bit more detail by exploring a few possible
ولذا، دعونا نتناول تلك بقدر أكبر بقليل من التفصيل، من خلال استعراض
cases.
بعض الحالات الممكنة.
So, the question is is ft good?
ولذا، فإن السؤال هو، هل (Ft) مناسبة؟
If ft is really good,
في حال كانت Ft جيدة مناسبة للغاية.
it has really low error with the training data that say, weighted error.
فسيكون بها خطأ أقل بالفعل فيما يخص بيانات التدريب، والذي يطلق عليه الخطأ المرجح.
So for example, if that weighted error is 0.01, then it's a really good classifier.
ولذا، وعلى سبيل المثال، إذا كان الخطأ المرجح يساوي 0.01، فمن ثم فهو يعتبر مصنِف مناسب.
The question is first, lets see what happens to this famous middle term here
والسؤال هو، ما الذي يحدث لهذا المصطلح المتوسط الشهير
when the weighted error is 0.01.
عندما يساوي الخطأ المرجح 0.01.
So the middle term is 1-0.01/0.01,
ولهذا فإن المصطلح في المنتصف سيكون 1-0.01 ÷ 0.01،
which is equal to 99.
والذي يساوي 99.
And next, to complete w hat t,
وبعد ذلك، ولتكملة Ŵt،
we're going to take a half times the log of this number 99.
سنقوم بأخذ ناتج ضرب 1/2 في اللوغاريتم للعدد 99،
And so if you do one-half times the log of 99,
ولهذا، إن قمت بضرب 1/2 في اللوغاريتم للعدد 99،
you're going to get 2.3.
فستحصل على 2.3.
So this was an excellent classifier and we gave it a weight of 2.3, which is high.
ولهذا، فإن ذلك يعتبر مصنِفًا ممتازًا، وقد أعطيناه ترجيحًا بنسبة 2.3، والذي يعتبر ترجيحًا مرتفعًا.
Now, let's see what happens if we output a random classifier.
والآن، دعونا نرى ماذا يحدث، إذا كان المُخرج لدينا مصنِف عشوائي،
So as we said, a random classifier has weighted error of
ولذا، فإننا كما قلنا إن المصنِف العشوائي، به خطأ مُرجح يساوي 0.5
0.5 is not something to be trusted.
فهو بذلك شيء لا يمكن الوثوق به.
So if you plug this in, 1-0.5/0.5,
ولذا، إذا قمت بتلك العملية الحسابية 1-0.5 ÷ 0.5
yields the magic number 1.
فستحصل على العدد السحري 1.
And if you look at a half of log of one, what's log of one?
وفي حال نظرت إلى 1/2 اللوغاريتم 1، فماذا سيكون اللوغاريتم 1؟
It's 0, so w hat t is 0.
فسيكون 0، ولذا فإن Ŵt ستكون 0.
So what we learn, if a classifier is just random,
ولذا، ما تعلمناه هو أن إذا كان المصنف عشوائي،
it's not doing anything meaningful.
فلن يقوم بأي شيء ذي معنى،
We count it by zero.
وسنقوم بحسابه باعتباره صفرًا.
We say, you're terrible, we're going to ignore you and
ويكأن لسان حالنا يقول، أنت فظيع، سنقوم بتجاهلك،
you might have friends who are kind of like this.
وقد يكون لديك زملاء يشبهون ذلك نوعًا ما،
They say random stuff,
ممن يقولون أشياءً عشوائية،
you never trust what they say, you put zero weight on their opinions.
ولا تثق أبدًا بما يقولونه، وتضع ترجيح يساوي 0 أمام آرائِهم.
So, that's what AdaBoost is too.
ولذا، هذا ما سيقوم به AdaBoost أيضًا.
Now we're going to get to a really, really, really interesting case.
والآن سيكون لدينا حالة مثيرة جدًا جدًا.
Let's suppose that your classify is terrible, it gets 0.99 weighted error.
دعونا نفترض أن التصنيف فظيع، وسيكون به خطأ مرجح يساوي 0.99.
So its getting almost everything wrong, it's worse than random.
ولذا، فإن كل ما به تقريبًا خطأ، ولذا يعد أسوأ من العشوائي،
Let's see what happens to the term in the middle here of our equation.
ودعونا نرى ماذا يحدث للمصطلح في المنتصف هنا في المعادلة التي لدينا،
You get 1-0.99/0.99,
أنت تحصل على 1-0.99 ÷ 0.99،
which is equal to 0.01 and
ويساوي الناتج 0.01،
guess what happens when you take a half log of 0.01?
وخمن ماذا قد يحدث عندما تأخذ 1/2 اللوغاريتم والذي يساوي 0.01؟
You get -2.3.
ستحصل على -2.3.
And when I first saw this, I thought, wow, this AdaBoost theorem is beautiful,
وعندما رأيت ذلك أولاً، قلت يا للروعة، إن نظرية AdaBoost هذه رائعة،
but take a moment to kind of internalize what just happened.
ولكني استغرقت لحظات، لفهم ماذا حدث للتو.
We had this terrible classifier.
لقد حصلنا على هذا المصنف الفظيع.
But yet, we gave it pretty high weight, 2.3, but
ولكننا أعطيناه ترجيحًا مرتفعًا للغاية وهو 2.3،
with a negative sign and why is that?
ولكن مع علامة سالبة، فلماذا ذلك؟
Because a terrible, terrible classifier might be terrible but if we take 1-f of t.
لأن المصنِف الفظيع جدًا، قد يكون فظيعًا ولكن إن أخذنا 1-Ft،
So if we do exactly the opposite of what it says, it's an awesome classifier.
فإننا سنقوم بالضبط بعكس ما يُقال، ولذا سيكون مصنِفًا رائعًا،
In other words, if we invert a classifier, we're going to do awesomely.
وبصيغة أخرى، إذا قمنا بعكس المصنف، فسيحدث ذلك بشكل رائع.
And AdaBoost automatically does that for you.
وتقوم نظرية AdaBoost بذلك تلقائيًا لك،
And so this is again, kind of the using the friend analogy.
وهذا مجددًا، يعتبر نوعًا من استخدام تناظر الصديق،
You might have a friend who always has really good opinions,
فقد يكون لديك، والذي يكون صاحب آراء جيدة تمامًا،
but they're all always like wrong.
ولكنها تبدو جميعها خاطئة.
And so, we do exactly the opposite of what that person says.
ولذا، نقوم بالضبط بعكس ما يقوله الشخص.
Maybe this is how you hear your parents or something, or some friends.
وربما يكون ذلك، مثل أن تسمع لوالديك أو أي شخص ما أو بعض الأصدقاء
You say, okay, you say, I should do A, I'm going to do the opposite of that.
وتقول حسنًا، حسنًا، يجب أن أقوم بكذا، ولكنك في قرارة نفسك ستقوم بعكسه.
And by doing that, I might do great things in the world.
ومن خلال القيام بذلك، قد أقوم بأشياء رائعة في العالم.
And so AdaBoost automatically figures that out for you, which is awesome.
ويقوم AdaBoost تلقائيًا باكتشاف ذلك لك، ويعتبر ذلك رائعًا.
Now lets revisit the AdaBoost algorithm that we've been talking about and
والآن، دعونا نعود مرة أخرى لخوارزمية AdaBoost والتي تحدثنا عنها قبل ذلك،
in this part of the module,
ومن خلال هذا الجزء من هذه الوحدة،
we're going to be exploring how do we compute the coefficient w hat t and
سنقوم بالتدقيق حول كيفية يتم حساب المعامل Ŵt،
we saw that can be computed by this really simple formula.
ولاحظنا أنه يمكن حساب ذلك من خلال هذه الصيغة البسيطة.
We compute the weighted error of f of t and we just say, w hat t is one-half
وقمنا بحساب الخطأ المُقدر لـ Ft وقلنا إن Ŵt تساوي 1/2 اللوغاريتم
of the log of 1 minus weighted error divided by the weighted error.
والذي به 1 - الخطأ المرجح ومقسومًا على الخطأ المرجح.
And with that, we have a w hat t and
ومن خلال ذلك، فسيكون لدينا Ŵt،
we can focus on figuring out how to come up with alpha Is.
وسيمكن التركيز على كيفية التوصل إلى Alpha IS،
And we want alpha i is to be high where ft makes mistakes or does [INAUDIBLE].
ونحن نود أن تكون α I أن تكون مرتفعة، عندما تقوم Ft بأخطاء أو (كلام غير مسموع )
[MUSIC]
[موسيقى]